JEFFREY CHIU

mr.jeffrey.chiu@gmail.com

+1.347.589.4735

NYC Metropolitan Area

• jeffreychiu.dev

github.com/jeffreyc86



• jeffrey-chiu.medium.com

PROFILE

A design-minded developer with a background in sales and client management. Experienced in JavaScript-based programming, especially React and Redux, as well as Ruby on Rails. Committed to consistency and transparency, dedicated to continuous development, and energized by a challenge.

SKILLS

JavaScript • React • Redux • Ruby on Rails • HTML • CSS • PostgresSQL • SQLite • Git • Webpack • Node.js • React Native

Fluent in Mandarin, Taiwanese, and Cantonese • Windows 10 • MAC OSX • Salesforce • CRM Systems • Microsoft Office Suite • Google Suite • Adobe Photoshop • Social Media

PROJECTS

Alteri (React, Redux, Rails, PostgesSQL, WebSockets, CSS)
Web app connecting those in need of basic necessities with donors

LIVE LINK





- Integrated WebSockets through ActionCable to enable an app where users are notified of requests being made.
 Upon acceptance of a request, the recipient and donor are assigned a real-time chat to coordinate exchange logistics.
- Employed Google Maps API to show the location of the recipient and donor, and fetch suggestions for public meeting locations within their vicinity.
- Enhanced global state management with Redux Toolkit for CRUD functions with a Rails RESTful API.
- Secured user authentication with Oauth and user info management.

Spreddit (React, Rails, PostgesSQL, CSS)

Functional Reddit clone to post about pandemic related topics







- Ensured a smooth user experience (UX) through React (hooks) and React Router for client-side routing.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Designed a RESTful API and implemented full CRUD functionality on posts, comments, and likes.

YouTravel (JavaScript, Rails, PostgresSQL, Bootstrap, CSS) **YouTube** inspired site focused exclusively on travel videos

LIVE LINK





- Developed a single page app enabling users to view and post videos based on a selected city and video category. To post a video, users use a YouTube URL which is then parsed and saved as the embed link on the backend.
- Manipulated the DOM, allowing users to see new videos, likes, and comments, as well as any changes in real-time.

EXPERIENCE

Factor

Analyst, Business Development

April 2019 – September 2020

New York, NY

- Drove growth via outbound approach. Called on C-Suite executives, General Counsels, and potential clients, to identify potential engagements for Factor's next-generation legal solutions focused around process, workflow software, and contract management technology.
- Developed and executed upon business plans in conjunction with various teams to build pipeline and revenue; resulting in 17 qualified opportunities totaling \$4 million across a variety of industries.
- Documented all activity within Salesforce.com; created reports, campaigns, and dashboards to track sales lifecycle.

Liagre, Inc

Account Executive

April 2018 - April 2019

New York, NY

- Increased brand exposure by cultivating relationships from an incumbent client book of over 400 interior design firms within eastern Canada, New York, and Washington DC.
- Identified stagnant accounts and developed customized plans, achieved \$1 million in sales within the first six months, 40% contributed from new leads or stagnant accounts.

Cassina

Assistant Showroom Manager, Account Executive

September 2014 – April 2018

New York, NY

- Ranked #1 nationally and #3 worldwide for sales in 2016, 2017, and first half of 2018.
- Managed high profile interior designers and clients to generate an average of \$1.3 million on an annual basis with a conversion rate of 80%.
- Oversaw and trained a team of three Account Executives; provided insight and support to ensure their continued success.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

March 2021

Immersive Full-Stack Web Development Program Access Scholarship Recipient

Bernard M. Baruch College

May 2013

BBA: Advertising & Marketing Communications

EXTRACURRICULARS

New York Cares

September 2014 - Present

Volunteer